

LEKSHMINARAYANAN K

■ karthik.kln@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/lekshminarayanan-k-46a35948

SUMMARY

9 years of experience involving in DevOps, Support-Deploying-Implementation-Administration on Kubernetes, Docker swarm, Docker UCP/DTR, Consul, Jenkins, Terraform, AWS Ansible/Chef, Git, SVN, Python, Shell Scripting, Virtualization, Server Deployment, Red Hat 4-5-6 servers, CentOS, VMware ESX platforms. Ubuntu client Desktops, Firewalls, Networking and Security products. Exceptional Problem Resolution, Client Relation, and Technology Management skills. Ability to build team cohesion and inspire colleagues to higher achievement. Excellent presentation, training, mentoring skills and Team leadership.

Publication: Technical reviewer of Centos high performance https://www.packtpub.com/networking-and-servers/centos-high-performance

EXPERIENCE

DevOps-Release Engineer

Dec 2017 - Present

System Analyst - Linux DevOps

Dec 2015 - Dec 2017

ADP

Busy Playing with Lifion's micro-services world.

Dealing with Kubernetes, Docker, Docker DTR, Consul, Jenkins, Terraform, AWS, Ansible, NPM, Kafka, Apache Kaka/Zookeeper, Ngnix, Mysql.

Emerio

I am enthusiastic and driven to learn and improve. I work well in an Agile environment with SCRUM/Kanban whether individually, supporting a team or placed within one.

Highlights:

- Linux admin, DevOps, Bash Scripting, Ansible/Chef
- Viewed as advocate for best practices, CI/Jenkins, unit and automated testing and SOLID principles.
- Expert with Linux, Bash, git
- Translated requirements into an "Automation" specification by shell scripting

Achievements:

- Designed CI/CD processes in the context of a Jenkins orchestration, including the usage of automated build, test/QA, and deployment tools Configure jobs and pipelines using Jenkins.
- Performed implementation of customer-specific automation
- Developed customer-agnostic, multi-functional automation
- Worked in remote team to build an Artifical Intelligence tool
- Experienced in source code maintenance in svn and git for branching, merging, release tagging and admin activities.

Additional: Git, Docker, Docker Swarm, Jenkins, Shell/bash, Terraform, Packer, vagrant, Virtualbox

NOC Linux system administrator

May 2013 - Dec 2015

Comodo | Chennai

Comodo IT Infrastructure Application Center – Providing Build, Release and configuration management for Production Servers, Applications management across the Global location data

- Member of Configuration and Release Management Team doing build, release
- Participated in workgroup to define and drive new release management process (scope definition, release cycle, activities, duration, milestones, entry/exit criteria, governance, roles & responsibilities, authority, escalation path etc).
- Develop & maintain scripts to automate the process of build and release.
- Work closely with the technology group, project teams and Operations to anticipate, document, and fulfill environmental needs for successful builds, and address environmental issues as they
- Maintenance of all major production release code streams.
- Facilitates for the shipment of all Patch Builds.

System Administrator

Feb 2010 - Apr 2013

• EdServ Softsystems Limited, Chennai

Extensive experience as an Linux (, Red Hat/Fedora, Red Hat Enterprise Linux Advanced Server, CentOS, Ubuntu) System Administrator.

Experience in the support of fundamental technologies such as DNS, SFTP/FTP, SMTP, SNMP, LDAP, SSL, SSH, TCP, UDP, IP, RAID, TFTP, BOOTP, DHCP, Kerberos, and SMB/CIFS.

Expertise in Unix/Linux system installation, configuration, administration, the development and testing of backup and recovery methodologies, troubleshooting, capacity and performance planning, performance tuning, preventative maintenance, monitoring and alerting setup and security hardening.

Produce and deliver reports on system utilization (processor, memory, disk, and network).

Shell scripting to automate system maintenance tasks

Configured Web-server (Apache HTTP server) in Cent OS and hosted a Website

Configured the Back-end database (MySQL) in and its user creation.

Configured the Front-end programming package (PHP) for developers

Client machines hosts configuration for appropriate LAMP server.

Scheduling back up on Cronjobs and managing backups

Installed and Configured VMware ESXi server 4.1

Installed and Configured vSphere Client and Vcenter in a Desktop machine

Virtual Storage configured as per the guest OS and Data requirements

Sphere Virtual Networking Maintained and Implemented

Guest OS Created on VMware ESXi server

Storage integrated between the four virtual OS

Configuration the Tasks, Events, and Alarms

Implementation and Maintenance vSphere Virtual Networking

Incorporates disk, tape, SAN, and storage software

Alert and resolve SAN storage performance issues and advise end users

PROJECTS

LAMP (Solution stack Project)

Apr 2011

Client: Edserv Soft Systems Ltd

Migration of Standalone webserver into Own Datacenter

Jun 2010

Client: Edserv Soft systems Ltd

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (BE): Electronics and Communications Engineering

Anna University

CERTIFICATIONS

CLOUDU CERTIFICATE

Issued Jan 2014No Expiration Date

Rackspace, the Cloud Company

RHCE - Red Hat Certified Engineer

Issued 2013No Expiration Date

Red Hat

Certified Kubernetes

Administrator

CNCF [Cloud Native Computing Foundation]

Issued Aug 2020Expires Sep 2023

Microsoft

RHCSA - Red Hat Certified System Administrator

Credential ID 130-072-994

SKILLS

Servers, Apache, DNS

Industry Knowledge: Linux System Administration, Virtualization, Shell Scripting, Firewalls, SAN, System Administration, Storage Area Networks, Storage, Data Center

Red Hat

Tools & Technologies: VMware ESX, VMware, MySQL, CentOS, PHP, Operating Systems, Docker, Jenkins, Apache 2, Ubuntu, Ansible

Other Skills: RHEL, LAMP administration, Linux Clustering, DevOps, Nagios, Linux Firewalls, Squid, FTP, Samba, Heartbeat, scri